[{"question": "What is the output of c program with structures.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct car\n    {int color;};\n    struct garage\n    {\n        struct car mycar[10];\n    }gar;\n    struct car c1={5};\n    gar.mycar[0]=c1;\n    printf(\"%d\",gar.mycar[0]);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) NULL", "option2": "B) 0", "option3": "C) 5", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is the size of the below C structure in TurboC?\nint main()\n{\n    struct books{\n        int pages;\n        char str[4];\n    }b;\n    printf(\"%d\",sizeof(b));\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) 5", "option2": "B) 6", "option3": "C) 7", "option4": "D) 8", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with Structure pointer in TurboC.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct books{\n        int pages;\n        char str[4];\n    }*ptr;\n    printf(\"%d\",sizeof(ptr));\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) 2", "option2": "B) 6", "option3": "C) 7", "option4": "D) 8", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "In a nested structure definition, with country.state.district statement, memeber state is actually present in the structure.? (COUNTY, STATE, DISTRICT structures)", "option1": "A) district", "option2": "B) state", "option3": "C) country", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is actually passed if you pass a structure variable to a function.?", "option1": "A) Copy of structure variable", "option2": "B) Reference of structure variable", "option3": "C) Starting address of structure variable", "option4": "D) Ending address of structure variable", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with structures.?\nvoid show(int,int);\nint main()\n{\n    struct paint{\n        int type;\n        int color;\n    }p;\n    p.type=1;\n    p.color=5;\n    show(p.type,p.color);\n    return 0;\n}\nvoid show(int a,int b)\n{\n    printf(\"%d %d\",a,b);\n}", "option1": "A) 1 1", "option2": "B) 1 5", "option3": "C) 5 1", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with structures.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct paint{\n        int type;\n        int color;\n    }p1, p2;\n    p1.type=1;\n    p1.color=5;\n    if(sizeof(p1)==sizeof(p2))\n    {\n        printf(\"SAME\");\n    }\n    else\n    {\n        printf(\"DIFFERENT\");\n    }\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) SAME", "option2": "B) DIFFERENT", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C structures.", "option1": "A) A structure enables display of folder structure in OS.", "option2": "B) A structure enables erasing contents in a folder in OS.", "option3": "C) A structure enables to detect and respond to mouse clicks.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about structure and array.?", "option1": "A) An array stores only elements of same type. Accessing elements is easy.", "option2": "B) A structure is preferred when different type elements are to be combined as a single entity.", "option3": "C) An array implementation has performance improvements to structure", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What are the types of data allowed inside a structure.?", "option1": "A) int, float, double, long double", "option2": "B) char, enum, union", "option3": "C) pointers and Same structure type members", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}]
